Leonardo Maria Del Vecchio, heir to the Ray-Ban fortune, is
escalating a battle for control.
He's publicly challenged his family's holding company, Delfin Sarl, to
back his 10 billion euro buyout of two siblings' stakes,
days before a crucial shareholder meeting.
In an open letter, Del Vecchio accused Delfin's board of
unclear explanations for its shifting position, calling it a governance
issue.
His plan seeks to make him the largest shareholder, ending
years of family divisions over the empire's succession.
The 10 billion euro deal requires complex financing, with lenders
seeking certainty on strategy.
Del Vecchio states Delfin's board couldn't unite on addressing these.
Now, an alternative sees Delfin buying back the stakes and
redistributing them among heirs.